Coalition of Adult Education Organizations (CAEO) Records
Coalition of Adult Education Organizations (CAEO) Records
1964-1991
1969-1985
Coalition of Adult Education Organizations
15 linear ft.
Records include Board of Directors’ minutes, agendas, memoranda, and reports; by-laws and articles of incorporation; committee files; conference programs; correspondence; drafts; newsletters, brochures and directories; and resolutions. Included are records from the Galaxy Conference (1969) and Wingspread Conference (1976); records of the Adult Education Action Council; and materials from UNESCO and the International Council for Adult Education, of which the Coalition is a founding member. Organizations represented include the Adult Education Association, Adult Student Personnel Association, American Association of Community and Junior Colleges, American Society for Training and Development, Association of University Evening Colleges, W.K. Kellogg Foundation, National Association of Public Continuing and Adult Education, National University Extension Association, and United States Association of Evening Students. Correspondents include Leonard P. Aries, Ray J. Ast, Alexander N. Charters, James R. Dorland, Norman D. Kurland, Charles J. Longacre, Constance J. McQueen, David Puddington, Yvonne K. Rappaport, Fran M. Spinelli, Hamilton Stillwell, Clarence H. Thompson, Willard L. Thompson, and Sandra Timmerman.
149434
Biographical History
The Coalition of Adult Education Organizations (CAEO) had its beginnings in the early 1960s as adult educators recognized the need for greater interaction among adult education organizations. Its purposes from the beginning have been 1) to provide a forum for the discussion of issues, 2) to encourage cooperation within the field, and 3) to gain greater support from both the government and the general public. Originally known as the Ad Hoc Committee of Adult Education Organizations (later as the Committee of Adult Education Organizations), its first meetings resulted in the document, "Imperatives for Action," and the 1969 Galaxy Conference, at which the "Imperatives" were adopted as the charter document for membership in the newly created Coalition of Adult Education Organizations. Formal incorporation was realized in 1973. There was, in these formative years, an unsuccessful attempt to create a distinct political action arm known as the Adult Education Action Council (AEAC).
In 1976, another conference was held at the Wingspread Conference Center, from which emerged the revised "Imperatives for Policy and Action in Lifelong Learning." It was widely disseminated and helped to heighten the public's awareness of and interest in lifelong learning.
The CAEO has been recognized for its impact on federal legislative actions. Other accomplishments include the successful petition for an adult and continuing education section of the ERIC clearinghouse and an active international presence through both UNESCO and the International Council for Adult Education (ICAE), of which the CAEO is a founding member.
The CAEO's primary value, however, has been in the improved cooperation among its members, enhancing the identification and clarification of issues in adult education, and promoting activities to support continuing education.
More details concerning the CAEO's history and activities are available in the following two documents found in the collection:
Glancy, Keith E., compiler. Coalition of Adult Education Organizations, 1964-1989: An Index of Actions and Materials. 1990. [Box 1]
Policicchio, Armand. The Coalition of Adult Education Organizations: An Historical and a Network Perspective. Ph.D. diss., University of Pittsburgh, 1984. [Box 15]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The records of the CAEO have been divided into several series to reflect the organization's filing practices. A complete synopsis of these series can be found immediately following this introduction. Inclusive dates for the collection are 1964-1991, the bulk dates, 1969-1985.
The series on CAEO Business is the largest, encompassing several subseries whose contents are self-explanatory. A few comments need to be made concerning the Minutes and Board of Directors subseries.
Minutes: This series remains relatively intact as received. It is a succinct record of CAEO activities, and includes meeting minutes, resolutions, important documents and membership directories.
Board of Directors: Although it includes most of the same material as the Minutes series, the Board of Directors series also provides the supporting material, agendas, correspondence and handouts which pertain to the individual meetings. Most of the materials pertaining to the Galaxy and Wingspread Conferences have been removed to a separate Conference subseries.
Most materials, including the Committees subseries, are filed chronologically, however, some materials are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Within alphabetical arrangements, proper names are filed by last name although they appear in direct order, and folders on a single project or organization are kept together and presented chronologically.
Adult Education Action Council contains correspondence, minutes, articles of incorporation and other material related to the Council.
Organizations, councils and commissions contains material relating to a wide range of organizations relating to adult education. Organizations represented here include Adult Education Association, Adult Student Personnel Association (ASPA), American Association for Adult and Continuing Education, American Council on Education (ACE), American Society for Training and Development (ASTD), Association of University Evening Colleges (AUEC), Council of Graduate Schools, Kellogg Foundation, National Advisory Council on Adult Education (NACAE), National Association of Black Adult Educators (NABAE), National Association for Public Continuing and Adult Education (NAPCAE), National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH), Project Literacy U.S. (PLUS), Syracuse University Resources for Educators of Adults, and several U.S. government departments and offices.
International organizations contains general information from the International Council for Adult Education (ICAE) and UNESCO, and conference material from six international adult education conferences
Papers and reports contains various internal CAEO reports, most self-reflective in nature (e.g. "CAEO Retrospective: The First Ten Years" or "CAEO Through the Years").
Miscellaneous contains clippings, dissertation material, and other assorted items, from both individuals and organizations, while Pamphlets, newsletters and flyers consists of short printed material relating to adult education, including Adult and Continuing Education Today and Lifelong Learning.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged either alphabetically or chronologically as appropriate. The method of arrangement for each series is given with the series descriptions in the inventory below.
Related Material
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education. Please refer to for a complete listing of all adult education collections. In particular, see the ERIC Clearinghouse on Adult Education Records, Galaxy Conference Records, Clarence H. Thompson Papers. and Willard Thompson Papers.
Separated Material
A number of pamphlets were removed and transferred to the Adult Education Pamphlets Collection. Also removed were the following publications, which can be found in the general collection (refer to ):
Learning. Vol. 4, No.2. Toronto: Canadian Association for Adult Education, 1985.
Literacy Discussion. Vol.?, No.4. Tehran, Iran: International Institute for Adult Literacy Methods, 1976.
Liveright, A.A. and DeCrow, Roger. New Directions in Degree Programs Especially for Adults. Chicago: Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1963.
National Advisory Council on Adult Education. A Target Population in Adult Education: Report of the National Advisory Council on Adult Education. Washington, D.C.: U.S. Government Printing Office, 1974.
National Advisory Council on Extension and Continuing Education. A Measure of Success: Federal Support for Continuing Education: 7th Annual Report and Recommendations of the National Advisory Council on Extension and Continuing Education. Washington, D.C.: U.S. Government Printing Office, 1973.
National Education Association of the United States. Combating Discrimination in the Schools: Legal Remedies and Guidelines. Washington, D.C.: National Education Association, 1973.
Thompson, Thomas, ed. The Schooling of Native America. Washington, D.C.: American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education, 1978.
Verner, Coolie, ed. Administration of Adult Education. Adult Education: Theory and Method, Vol. 7. Washington, D.C.: Adult Education Association of the Q.S.A., 1965.
White, Thurman James. The Promise and Pragmatism of Adult Education. Syracuse, N.Y.: Syracuse University, 1979.
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Charters, Alexander N.; Kurland, Norman D. (Norman David), 1927-; Spinelli, Fran M.; Thompson, Willard L.; Aries, Leonard P.; Ast, Ray J.; Dorland, James R.; Longacre, Charles J.; McQueen, Constance J.; Puddington, David.; Rappaport, Yvonne K.; Stillwell, Hamilton.; Thompson, Clarence H.; Timmerman, Sandra.; Adult Education Association.; American Association of Community and Junior Colleges.; American Society for Training and Development.; Association of University Evening Colleges (U.S.); Coalition of Adult Education Organizations, Archives.; ERIC Clearinghouse on Adult Education.; International Council for Adult Education.; W.K. Kellogg Foundation.; National University Extension Association.; Unesco.; United States Association of Evening Students.; Adult Education Action Council.; Adult Student Personnel Association.; National Association of Public Continuing and Adult Education.; Galaxy Conference on Adult Education (1969: Washington, D.C.); Wingspread Conference on Adult Education (1976: Racine, Wis.); Adult education -- Research.; Agendas (administrative records); Brochures.; Correspondence.; Directories.; Drafts (documents); Memorandums.; Minutes (administrative records); Newsletters.; Notes (documents); Pamphlets.; Programs (documents); Reports.; Resolutions.; Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
### (MARC 541 and/or 561)
Inventory
- Indexes
  - Index of actions and materials, 1964-1989 (Box 1)
  - Inventory of Folder Titles as Received by George Arents Library, 1991 (Box 16)
- CAEO business
  - Minutes, 1964-1990 (Box 1)
  - Board of directors (chron.)
    - Ad Hoc Committee of Adult Education Organizations, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - Committee of Adult Education Organizations, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
    - Board of Directors, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Sept. 28 1970 (Box 1)
    - Jan. 15 1971 (Box 1)
    - June 7-8 1971 (Box 1)
    - Sept. 26-27 1971 (Box 1)
    - Feb. 3-4 1972 (Box 1)
    - March 20-21 1972 (Box 1)
    - June 15-16 1972 (Box 1)
    - Nov. 9-10 1972 (Box 2)
    - Agenda Items, 1973 (Box 2)
    - March 1-2 1973 (Box 2)
    - June 24-25 1973 (Box 2)
    - June 25-26 1973 (Box 2)
    - Aug. 15 1973 (Box 2)
    - Nov. 14-15 1973 (Box 2)
    - ICAE Agenda Materials, 1974 (Box 2)
    - March 11-12 1974 (Box 2)
    - June 1974 (Box 2)
    - June 26-27 1974 (Box 2)
    - Dec. 5-6 1974 (Box 2)
    - Charles Longacre, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
    - March 12-14 1975 (Box 3)
    - June 26-27 1975 (Box 3)
    - Dec. 4-6 1975 (Box 3)
    - March 11-12 1976 (Box 3)
    - June 24-25 1976 (Box 3)
    - Institute for Educational Leadership, Dec. 4-5 1976 (Box 3)
    - Dec. 9-10 1976 (Box 3)
    - Possible Agenda Items, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - March 10-11 1977 (Box 3)
    - June 23-24 1977 (Box 3)
    - Oct. 16-18 1977 (Box 3)
    - Feb. 23-24 1978 (Box 3)
    - June 22-23 1978 (Box 3)
    - Oct 12-13 1978 (Box 4)
    - Feb. 22-23 1979 (Box 4)
    - June 21-22 1979 (Box 4)
    - Charles Longacre, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
    - Oct. 25-26 1979 (Box 4)
    - Frances M. Spinelli, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
    - Feb. 21-22 1980 (Box 4)
    - Presidential Roundtable, Feb. 22 1980 (Box 4)
    - Tenth Anniversary Meeting -- Presidential Remarks, 1980 (Box 4)
    - June 5-6 1980 (Box 4)
    - Oct. 23-24 1980 (Box 4)
    - Dec.(?) 1980 (Box 4)
    - March 5-6 1981 (Box 4)
    - June 18-19 1981 (Box 5)
    - Oct. 22-23 1981 (Box 5)
    - Responsibilities and Guidelines, 1982 (Box 5)
    - March 1-2 1982 (Box 5)
    - June 17-18 1982 (Box 5)
    - Oct. 7-8 1982 (Box 5)
    - Feb. 3-4 1983 (Box 5)
    - June 9-10 1983 (Box 5)
    - Oct. 6-7 1983 (Box 5)
    - Feb. 2-3 1984 (Box 5)
    - June 7-8 1984 (Box 5)
    - Oct. 18-19 1984 (Box 5)
    - Feb. 7-8 1985 (Box 5)
    - June 20-21 1985 (Box 5)
    - Oct. 24-25 1985 (Box 5)
    - Feb. 6-7 1986 (Box 5)
    - June 19-20 1986 (Box 5)
    - Oct. 9-10 1986 (Box 5)
    - Guidelines, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Feb. 5-6 1987 (Box 5)
    - Strategic Planning, Feb. 5-6 1987 (Box 5)
    - June 18-19 1987 (Box 5)
    - Oct. 20-21 1987 (Box 5)
    - Mar. 22-23 1988 (Box 5)
    - June 16-17 1988 (Box 6)
    - Feb. 23-24 1989 (Box 6)
    - June 15-16 1989 (Box 6)
    - Oct. 26-27 1989 (Box 6)
    - Feb. 22-23 1990 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence (chron.)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1974 (Box 6)
    - University of D.C., 1974-1975 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
    - Incoming--Constance McQueen, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 6)
    - Charles Longacre, 1979-1980 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 7)
    - ICAE, 1980 (Box 7)
    - Sandra Timmerman, 1980-1981 (Box 7)
    - Frances Spinelli, 1980-1981 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Sandra Timmerman, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Frances Spinelli, 1982 (Box 7)
    - TV Project, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Frances Spinelli, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Patrick Mullarney, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1990 (Box 7)
  - Committee files (chron.)
    - Advertising Council, 1969-1974 (Box 7)
    - Executive, 1971 (Box 7)
    - Advertising Council Project, 1971-1975 (Box 7)
    - Advertising Council--Proposal Drafts, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Advertising Council, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Steering, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Advertising Council, 1972-1973 (Box 7)
    - ERIC/AE, 1972-1975 (Box 7)
    - Steering, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Executive, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Public Information, 1974 (Box 7)
    - Steering Committee on Lifelong Learning, 1974(?) (Box 7)
    - Census, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
    - Committee on Continuing Education, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
    - Human Rights, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
    - International Programs, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
    - Issues Committee--Kurland Papers, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
    - Legislative, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
    - Membership, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
    - Nominating, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
    - Ways and Means, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
    - Advertising and Public Information, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Executive, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Information Systems, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Joint Committee to Consider Reorganization, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Policy Planning and Data Collection, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Steering, 1975 (Box 8)
    - International Associates Selection, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Policy Planning and Data Collection, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Steering, 1976 (Box 8)
    - International Programs, 1976-1977 (Box 8)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on CAEO Constitution and By-Laws, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Human Rights, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - International Associates, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Legislative, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Publicity and Public Relations, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Calendar Coordination, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Committee on Continuing Education for Educators of Adults, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Executive, 1978 (Box 8)
    - International Associates, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Membership, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Nominating, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Public Policy and Data Collection, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Data Collection, 1978-1980 (Box 8)
    - Executive, 1979 (Box 8)
    - International Associates, 1979 (Box 8)
    - Executive, 1980 (Box 8)
    - International Associates, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Party Platform, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Department of Education, 1980-1981 (Box 8)
    - Executive, 1981 (Box 8)
    - International Associates, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Nominating, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Public Information, 1981-1982 (Box 8)
    - International Associates, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Committee Assignments, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
    - Future Directions, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
    - International Associates, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on CAEO Purposes, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Major Issues in Adult Education, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Executive, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Future Directions, 1982 (Box 9)
    - International Associates, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Committees, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
    - Fiscal Health, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
    - Committee on Adult learner, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Executive, 1983 (Box 9)
    - By-Laws, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
    - International Associates, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
    - Executive, 1984 (Box 9)
    - International Associates, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Executive, 1985 (Box 9)
    - International Associates, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
    - Future Directions Task Force, 1986-1987 (Box 9)
    - International Associates, 1987-1988 (Box 9)
  - Membership (chron.)
    - Voting representatives, 1970-1975 (Box 9)
    - Membership, 1972-1981 (Box 9)
    - Membership, membership survey, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
    - Membership, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Legal matters (alphabetical)
    - Archive disposition, 1977-1978 (Box 9)
    - Articles of Incorporation, 1973 (Box 9)
    - Articles of Incorporation, revised, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Constitution and by-laws, 1969-1981 (Box 9)
    - Incorporation--application, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Legal counsel--Dorothy Wilson, 1977-1979 (Box 9)
    - Tax exempt status, 1974-1982 (Box 9)
    - Tax exempt status--application, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
    - Tax exempt status--Dorothy Wilson, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
    - Tax exempt status, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Taxes--District of Columbia, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Conferences (chron.)
    - Galaxy Conference (1969)
      - Planning Materials, 1968-? (Box 10)
      - General Information, 1969 (Box 10)
      - Press Folder, 1969 (Box 10)
      - Program, 1969 (Box 10)
      - Robert Allen, 1969 (Box 10)
      - Speeches, 1969 (Box 10)
      - Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 10)
      - Financial Reports, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Wingspread Conference (1976)
      - Johnson Foundation, 1974-1977 (Box 10)
      - Planning--Mini-Wingspread, 1975 (Box 10)
      - Background Materials, Notes, 1975-1976 (Box 10)
      - Pre-Conference Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 10)
      - Pre-Conference Comments on Imperatives for Action, 1975-1976 (Box 10)
      - Planning Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 10)
      - Applicants for Coordinator, 1976(?) (Box 10)
      - Correspondence--David Puddington, 1976 (Box 10)
      - Participants--Invitations, 1976 (Box 10)
      - Participants, 1976 (Box 10)
      - Participants--non-CAEO, 1976 (Box 10)
      - Participants--Regrets, 1976 (Box 10)
      - Minutes, Agendas, Reports, 1976 (Box 10)
      - Opening Remarks, 1976 (Box 10)
      - Robert Allen, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
      - Wingspread Conference, 1976 (Box 10)
      - Documents, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
      - Imperatives for Action--Draft Copies, 1976 (Box 10)
      - Imperatives for Action--1000 Influentials, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
      - Imperatives for Action--Requests, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
      - Imperatives for Action--Barasch Synthesis, 1977-1978 (Box 10)
      - Kellogg Foundation--Corres., 1976-1978 (Box 11)
      - Kellogg Foundation--Grant, 1976-1978 (Box 11)
      - Kellogg Foundation--Proposal Development, 1977 (Box 11)
      - Kellogg Foundation--Draft Proposal, 1977-1978 (Box 11)
      - Kellogg Foundation--Draft Proposal--Reactions, 1977 (Box 11)
      - Kellogg Foundation--Final Report, 1977 (Box 11)
      - Kellogg Foundation--Grant Proposal, 1977 (Box 11)
      - Kellogg Foundation--Draft Proposal II--Notes, 1978 (Box 11)
      - Post-Conference Corres., 1976-1978 (Box 11)
      - Wingspread Conference, 1977 (Box 11)
      - Follow-up, 1977 (Box 11)
      - Post-Conference Reports, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Legislative activities (chron.)
    - Legislative Activities, 1972-1973 (Box 11)
    - General Subcommittee on Education--Testimony, March 5 1973 (Box 11)
    - General Subcommittee on Education--Testimony, S.1814, June 28 1973 (Box 11)
    - Legislative Activities, 1974 (Box 11)
    - Lifelong Learning Legislation, 1974-1976 (Box 11)
    - Legislative Representatives--Full Funding, 1978-1979 (Box 11)
    - Legislative Activities, 1981-1984 (Box 11)
  - Projects (alphabetical)
    - Advertising Council Project, 1972-1973 (Box 11)
    - China Tour--Proposal, 1975 (Box 11)
    - Community Education Project, 1975-1978 (Box 11)
    - Community Education/Lifelong Learning Report, 1977-1978 (Box 11)
    - ERIC/AE Clearinghouse, 1973 (Box 11)
    - National Clearinghouse on Adult Education (ERIC/AE) Proposal, 1975 (Box 11)
    - Staff Funding Proposal, 1978 (Box 11)
    - TV Project--Grant Proposal, 1981 (Box 11)
    - TV Project, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - TV Project--Interim Report, 1983 (Box 11)
    - TV Project--Final Report, 1983 (Box 11)
    - TV Project--Domestic Policy Association, 1983 (Box 11)
    - TV Project--PBS Materials, 1983 (Box 11)
    - TV Project--PBS Materials--Guides and Catalogs, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Whither CAEO?, 1976-1977 (Box 12)
  - Printed materials (alphabetical)
    - Announcements, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
    - Brochures, 1972-1977 (Box 12)
    - Brochures and Stationery, 1978-1979 (Box 12)
    - Directories, International Associates, 1983-1985 (Box 12)
    - Leadership Directories and member lists, 1972-1982; 1986-1992; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Leadership Directory and brochures, 1977-1978 (Box 12)
    - Leadership Directory information, 1977-1986 (Box 12)
    - Newsletters, Directory, 1974-1976 (Box 12)
    - Newsletters, 1974-1976 (Box 12)
    - Newsletters--"Material not prepared," Winter, 1976 (Box 12)
    - Newsletters--International Associates, 1982-1990 (Box 12)
    - Stationery, 1976(?) (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Misc., 1968-1970 (Box 12)
    - Misc., 198-? (Box 12)
    - CAEO Award, 1974(?) (Box 12)
    - CAEO Award, 1979-1981 (Box 12)
    - Patricia Cross, 1986 (Box 12)
    - Financial Statements, 1970-1975 (Box 12)
    - Ford Foundation--Rejection, 1973 (Box 12)
    - Platform Statements, 1972 (Box 12)
    - Platform Recommendations, 1980 (Box 12)
    - Press Releases, 1974-1985 (Box 12)
    - Survey, 1986 (Box 12)
- Adult Education Action Council
  - Articles of Incorporation, By-Laws, 1971-1975 (Box 12)
  - Receipts, 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - Financial Records, 1971-1975 (Box 12)
  - Meetings, Memoranda, Reports, 1971-1974 (Box 12)
  - Board Meeting, Jan. 24-25 1972 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 12)
  - Willard Thompson, 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - misc., 1972 (Box 12)
- Organizations, councils, commissions (alphabetical)
  - List, 1971 (Box 13)
  - Action Agenda Project, 1985-1987 (Box 13)
  - Action Agenda--Postsecondary Rural Education--Proceedings, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
  - Adult Education Association, 1980 (Box 13)
  - Adult Education Legislative Workshop, Feb. 26-27, 1973 (Box 13)
  - Adult Learning Program Service, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
  - Adult Student Personnel Association (ASPA), 1973 (Box 13)
  - Advisory Council of National Organizations (ACNO)/ Corporation for Public Broadcasting (CPB), 1974-1975 (Box 13)
  - American Association for Adult and Continuing Education (AAACE), 1983-1985 (Box 13)